<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omics analysis for stratification of chronic inflammatory lung diseases.</title>
      <link>/talk/kiel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/kiel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full list of publication</title>
      <link>/publication/full/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/full/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration of multi-omics datasets enables molecular classification of COPD</title>
      <link>/publication/conference-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/conference-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make sense of your data: Clustering and multi-omics integration.</title>
      <link>/talk/berlin2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/berlin2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Boolean network inference</title>
      <link>/project/pbn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pbn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probabilistic Boolean network inference by integrating expression with network data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probabilistic Boolean networks (PBNs) were firstly introduced by Ilya Shmulevich in 2002, to be used as a rule-based uncertainty model for gene regulatory networks or cell signaling network. It is possible to perform model training, validation and model-based prediction to investigate the dynamic behavior of cells or tissues in response to a stimulus, and to understand the mechanism of a specific phenotype. We developed a new strategy and toolbox - PBNinfer, to infer PBNs by integrating the known gene regulatory network with time-course gene expression data. Based on the inferred PBN, we could answer four kinds of biological questions: 1) prediction of direct or indirect regulators of specific targets; 2) construction of sub-models and pathways of interesting processes or functions; 3) prediction of dynamic behavior of cell based on simulation analysis in response to a stimulus, perturbed gene or a specified initial state; and 4) identification of key regulators that drive conversion between PBN states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A logical model for retinoic acid (RA) signaling based on REF data and literature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to understand the beneficial as well as the undesirable effects of treating mouse skin with tRA. We inferred a PBN for tRA-treated mouse skin with 243 genes, 518 transcriptional factor-target interactions, and 2,143 Boolean functions. It revealed multiple activation pathways for COL1A1 and COL1A2 via STAT3 consistent with well-understood literature reports. We have tested the predictions of the model with different small molecule inhibitors of STAT3 as well as inhibitors directed against other pathways that regulate COL1A1. Reliable understanding of how tRA affects the skin will lead to more rational treatments to enhance skin health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RVi33JqjOQQcSuHIBRpyTldzVkMgBVIk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Poster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Medicine of COPD</title>
      <link>/project/a-snf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/a-snf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systems Medicine of COPD: Multi-‘OMICS based Molecular Sub-phenotyping of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease using Network Modeling Approaches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COPD is an increasing global health problem of pandemic proportions, which is likely to be caused by a multitude of etiologies including environmental exposures, genetic predispositions and developmental factors. Molecular sub-phenotyping and mechanistic modeling of COPD will therefore be essential in order to develop relevant diagnostic and treatment options. The development of computational systems medicine approaches and the availability of large-scale multi-omics datasets has provided the means to elucidate systematical alterations in the complex etiology of COPD. The project combines state-of-the-art systems medicine methodology and multi-omics datasets, representing a paradigm shift in the study of COPD and obstructive airway diseases. Expected results include not only improved understanding of COPD on a systems level, but also an in-depth probing of the nature of the inflammatory process in the lung. Subsequently, the results from this study may lead to improved techniques for early diagnosis of COPD as well as novel therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COPD represents an umbrella diagnosis, with a number of different etiologies arising from an intricate interaction of environmental and hereditary factors. Two major hypotheses will be investigated: 1) we hypothesize that bridging and integration of multi-molecular- level data with environmental and clinical factors will provide improved power for subclassification and identification of COPD pathophenotypes, and that these sub-phenotypes can be investigated as function modules in molecular networks.; 2) we hypothesize that
comparative analysis of molecular networks from COPD, resilient “healthy” smokers, and never-smoker controls can lead to identification of resilience mediators potentially protecting ‘healthy’ at-risk smokers from developing disease&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary objective is to identify module-based biomarkers by integration-analysis of multi-omics data using network biology approaches, with subsequent module-based sub-phenotyping. In systems medicine, the mechanism of disease is not only caused by independent subsets of genes/proteins/metabolites identifiable by traditional statistics, but also by their interactions, making it important to develop a system-level understanding of disease. Disease subnetworks within specific cell-types, as well as exosome-mediated regulation between immune- and structural cells will be investigated. Furthermore, a probabilistic Boolean Network (PBN) model for COPD will be inferred, providing a dynamic view of pathology and potential prediction of therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@supported by ERS/EU Marie Curie postdoc followship&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
