<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>瑞典卡罗林斯卡医学院肺组学研究小组博士后、访问学者和国家公派留学生招聘公告（生物医学方向）</title>
      <link>/post/biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/biology/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;一-简介&#34;&gt;一、简介&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;瑞典卡罗林斯卡医学院(Karolinska Institute)位于瑞典首都斯德哥尔摩， 建立于 1810 年，是世界知名医学院，以国际领先的科研水平和评审颁发诺贝尔 生理学医学奖而闻名。该校在英国泰晤士高等教育(Times Higher Education) 2017-2018 年世界高校排名居 38 位，是唯一挤身世界大学排名前 50 位的医科院校(&lt;a href=&#34;https://ki.se/en）&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://ki.se/en）&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;卡罗林斯卡研究所-索尔纳市医学系-呼吸内科&#34;&gt;卡罗林斯卡研究所，索尔纳市医学系，呼吸内科&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;索尔纳大学医学系是Karolinska学院最大的系之一。该系由几个部门组成，分为不同的研究小组。该系的核心活动是针对医学和生物医学学生的研究，博士教育和本科教育。该研究具有三个主要方面：过敏，心血管医学和炎性疾病。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;二-研究小组&#34;&gt;二、研究小组&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;博士后、访问学者和博士生研究员将是肺组学（Pulmonomics）研究小组（www.pulmonomics.net）的一部分，该小组由Solna分子医学中心和医学系呼吸内科的ÅsaWheelock副教授领导，李传星研究员参与指导(www.cxli.net)。我们的研究兴趣可以广义地定义为开发用于肺部慢性炎症疾病的分子亚表型的呼吸系统医学框架。我们将同等的精力集中于对患者人群对环境污染的响应的转化研究，以及蛋白质组学，多元建模和数据集成领域的创新与方法开发。我们的转化系统医学研究包括使用多种组学平台，结合多种肺功能，从多个肺区室（气道上皮，肺泡巨噬细胞，外泌体和支气管肺泡渗出液）以多种分子水平（mRNA，miRNA，蛋白质组，代谢组和脂质介体）进行分析广泛的临床表型。我们方法的优势在于能够整合来自多个分子水平和解剖位置的信息，从而提高检测和定义小型患者队列中分子不同的亚组的统计能力，并增进我们对系统水平上疾病机制的了解。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;三-项目&#34;&gt;三、项目&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们为2至3名博士后，访问学者和博士生研究人员开放，希望加入一个多学科系统医学项目，研究早产在阻塞性肺疾病发展中的作用。成功的候选人将加入一个由临床医师，实验科学家，统计学家和生物信息学家组成的大型研究团队，以研究早期生命事件在早期阻塞性肺疾病发展中的作用。整个项目涉及多个肺区室的mRNA，miRNA，蛋白质组和代谢组数据的分子表征，以构建疾病模型。这项工作将在我们独特的LUNAPRE队列（www.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02923648）上进行，该队列由非常早产的新生儿或患有支气管肺不典型增生（BPD）的婴儿组成，这些婴儿自出生以来就一直受到关注。以及足月出生的健康和哮喘患者的对照组。该项目的总体目标涉及在这个异质性，相对未知且发展迅速的患者群体中进行阻塞性肺疾病的分子亚表型分析和机理研究。具体的研究项目将根据成功候选人的经验和兴趣进行调整，其中可能包括RNA-seq，miRNA-seq以及各种区室的蛋白质组学表征，这些区室包括单细胞或大体积分类的免疫细胞以及来自肺的细胞外囊泡。患者队列以及细胞培养模型系统。这项研究是与卡罗林斯卡大学医院和斯德哥尔摩南部医院的萨克儿童医院的临床医生密切合作进行的，从而使成功的候选人能够直接参与转化系统医学的研究。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;四-资历和个人素质&#34;&gt;四、资历和个人素质&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们正在寻找具有博士学位的，有才华和积极性的研究人员。在相关学科中，最好是分子生物学，生物化学，系统医学或与组学相关的领域，生物信息学或生物统计学。具有呼吸领域的实践经验，CRISPR介导的基因编辑经验和/或结合湿实验室和生物统计学/生物信息学的经验是值得的。成功的候选人必须具有良好的沟通和协作能力，并且必须具备出色的英语听说读写能力。具有出色的沟通能力，以及与实验室中的其他博士后和学生以及与各种网络中的合作者进行社交和科学互动的能力至关重要。以前的博士后经验和出色的出版记录是很有价值的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;五-条款和条件&#34;&gt;五、条款和条件&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;招收中国国家留学基金管理委员公派博士后、访问学者和博士生，同时招收非公派博士后和访问学者。
博士后和访问学者职位是基于奖学金津贴的。津贴水平与经验水平相当，并包括医疗保健福利。这些职位最初是全职1年，可以延长到4年。要有资格获得基于津贴的博士后职位，申请人必须：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在征聘日期之前尚未居住在该国（瑞典）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在招聘日期之前尚未在该国家（瑞典）受雇
注：国家公派人员，在国家公派资助基础上，依据瑞典KI生活标准，课题组会补发一定生活补助。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;六-评估标准&#34;&gt;六、评估标准&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;上述重点研究领域的专业知识以及已证明的协作能力将是评估的主要基础。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;七-申请流程&#34;&gt;七、申请流程&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;申请书必须包含以下英文或中文文件：求职信，履历和研究愿景与经验的简短描述（最多2页），以及3个推荐人的联系信息。
        申请国家公派项目的人员，请将英文或中文材料发送至chuan-xing.li@ki.se，联系人：李老师
        申请非公派博士后的人员后续将通过KI job系统提交申请。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;申请截止时间：国家公派项目以2020年申请时间标准为准。非公派申请截止时间2019-11-25。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>瑞典卡罗林斯卡医学院肺组学研究小组博士后、访问学者和国家公派留学生招聘公告（计算生物学方向）</title>
      <link>/post/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;瑞典卡罗林斯卡医学院肺组学研究小组 博士后、访问学者和国家公派留学生招聘公告 （计算生物学方向）&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;一、简介&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;瑞典卡罗林斯卡医学院(Karolinska Institute)位于瑞典首都斯德哥尔摩， 建立于 1810 年，是世界知名医学院，以国际领先的科研水平和评审颁发诺贝尔 生理学医学奖而闻名。该校在英国泰晤士高等教育(Times Higher Education) 2017-2018 年世界高校排名居 38 位，是唯一挤身世界大学排名前 50 位的医科院校(&lt;a href=&#34;https://ki.se/en）&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://ki.se/en）&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;卡罗林斯卡研究所，索尔纳市医学系，呼吸内科&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;索尔纳大学医学系是Karolinska学院最大的系之一。该系由几个部门组成，分为不同的研究小组。该系的核心活动是针对医学和生物医学学生的研究，博士教育和本科教育。该研究具有三个主要方面：过敏，心血管医学和炎性疾病。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;二、研究小组&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们肺组学研究小组（www.pulmonomics.net）由临床医师，实验科学家，统计学家和生物信息学家组成，拟招聘2-3名的博士后、访问学者和博士生加入我们的团队，届时由Solna分子医学中心和医学系呼吸内科的李传星研究员 (www.cxli.net)和Åsa Wheelock副教授共同指导。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;课题组建有多种组学数据平台，并结合肺功能，从多个肺区室（气道上皮，肺泡巨噬细胞，外泌体和支气管肺泡渗出液）以多种分子水平（mRNA，miRNA，蛋白质组，代谢组和脂质介体）进行分析广泛的临床表型；同时开发能够整合多个分子水平和解剖位置的信息来提高检测和定义患者疾病亚型的算法。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;主要研究方向包括：1）基于多组学平台技术开发用于肺部慢性炎症疾病的分子亚表型的呼吸系统医学框架；2）对患者人群对环境污染的响应的转化研究；3）蛋白质组学，多元建模和数据集成领域的创新与方法开发。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;三、资历和个人素质&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们拟接受中国国家留学基金管理委员公派博士后、访问学者和博士生，同时招收非公派的博士后和访问学者。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;主要职责&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   开发和维护编程工具和工作流程，以自动进行生物数据分析&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   设计和开发用于管理生物数据的数据库和界面&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   处理，整合和分析生物学数据集，以揭示可验证假设的见解&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   通过文献回顾和计算实验来掌握最新的生物信息学工具&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   非公派候选人将协助部分资金项目申请&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   为致力于改善健康状况的转化研究人员小组做出贡献&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;要求&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   生物信息学，计算生物学，计算机科学或相关领域的硕士学位或博士学位&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   在处理，管理和整合生物数据集方面的丰富经验&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   精通R和Bioconductor软件包，一种或多种编程语言（Python，Perl等）和数据库（MongoDB，MYSQL等）&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   熟悉基因组学，统计学和生物信息学的基本概念&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   出色的口头和书面合作与沟通能力&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;优先选择&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   在组学分析方面具有丰富的生物信息学工具经验。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   擅长统计和机器学习&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   具有R包或基于Web的可视化工具开发方面的经验&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   熟悉高性能计算环境和云服务/管理系统&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   熟悉云服务和云管理系统&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   成功的候选人还将具有出色的协作技能，并具有在多学科团队中工作的经验。个人适应性和科学能力受到高度重视。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;四、条款和条件&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;对接受的博士后、访问学者及博士生，我们将提供奖学金津贴及医疗保健福利。申请时间最低一年，最多可延长至4年。有资格获得基于津贴的博士后职位，申请人必须：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   在征聘日期之前尚未居住在该国（瑞典）&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   在招聘日期之前尚未在该国家（瑞典）受雇 注：国家公派人员，在国家公派资助基础上，依据瑞典KI生活标准，课题组会补发一定生活补助。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;五、评估标准&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;上述重点研究领域的专业知识以及已证明的协作能力将是评估的主要基础。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;六、申请流程&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;申请书必须包含以下英文或中文文件：求职信，履历和研究愿景与经验的简短描述（最多2页），以及3个推荐人的联系信息。 申请国家公派项目的人员，请将英文或中文材料发送至chuan-xing.li@ki.se，联系人：李老师 申请非公派博士后的人员后续将通过KI job系统提交申请。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;申请截止时间：国家公派项目以2020年申请时间标准为准。非公派申请长期有效。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&lt;center&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/4.0/80x15.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;p style = &#34;font-size:10px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omics integration for sub-phenotyping of the spectrum diagnoses asthma and COPD</title>
      <link>/project/mats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COPD and asthma are umbrella diagnoses, and current diagnosis based on clinical characteristics alone is not sufficient. Molecular descriptors of disease sub-phenotypes are desperately needed to stratify patient populations for optimal diagnosis and treatment. We aim to utilize our recently developed systems medicine framework to facilitate identification of molecularly distinct sub- phenotypes of them in two systematical multi-omics cohorts, to help stratify these heterogeneous populations into molecularly distinct entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alterations in mRNA, microRNA, proteomes, metabolomes, and lipid mediators from multiple anatomical locations have been quantified in two clinical cohorts specifically designed for systems medicine investigations. Data will be integrated using newly developed computational systems biology approaches in multi-omics integration and disease module biomarker identification. We found that integration of 5-7 omics data-blocks enabled 100% correct classification of COPD diagnosis with groups as small as n=6 individuals, despite strong confounding effects of current smoking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stratification of the large spectrum of chronic obstructive lung diseases that today are housed under the umbrella diagnoses asthma and COPD represents a first, essential step to facilitate the development of new diagnostic tools and pharmaceutical targets for this debilitating spectrum of diseases, eventually reducing healthcare costs, improving quality of life, and saving lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding&lt;/strong&gt;: Mats Klebergs Stiftelse for 100 000 SEK; Research funding from Karolinska Institutet 2017-2021 for 80 000 SEK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roles&lt;/strong&gt;: Principal Investigator&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-omics analysis for stratification of chronic inflammatory lung diseases.</title>
      <link>/talk/kiel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/kiel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full list of publication</title>
      <link>/publication/full/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/full/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular phenotyping of endemic lung diseases (MORPHEUS)</title>
      <link>/project/lunapre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/lunapre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is a global health problem of pandemic proportions, affecting 10% of the population, 20% of which have never smoked. COPD is an umbrella diagnosis, and current diagnosis based on clinical characteristics alone is not sufficient. There is no cure or long-term effective treatment for obstructive lung disease. Molecular descriptors of disease sub-phenotypes are desperately needed to stratify patient populations for optimal diagnosis and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the MORPHEUS project, we will perform systems medicine investigations of 3 clinically well-characterized cohorts to facilitate identification of molecularly distinct disease sub-phenotypes, and molecular pathways critical for the associated pathological mechanisms. Secondary goals include evaluation of wearable sensors (“smart-bands”) and a custom smartphone app for cost effective longitudinal home-monitoring of patients, to prevent adverse events and aid patients in self-management of disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project aims to increase the precision of diagnosis of obstructive lung disease by providing quantitative molecular profiles of disease. Results may lead to development of new diagnostic tools and pharmaceutical targets for this debilitating spectrum of diseases, thereby reducing healthcare costs, improving quality of life, and saving lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding&lt;/strong&gt;: Large Research Grant from the Sweden Heart-lung fundation (&lt;strong&gt;Hjärt-Lungfonden&lt;/strong&gt;) for 15 000 000 SEK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roles&lt;/strong&gt;: Co-applicant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lunapre.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration of multi-omics datasets enables molecular classification of COPD</title>
      <link>/publication/conference-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/conference-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make sense of your data: Clustering and multi-omics integration.</title>
      <link>/talk/berlin2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/berlin2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Medicine of COPD</title>
      <link>/project/a-snf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/a-snf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systems Medicine of COPD: Multi-‘OMICS based Molecular Sub-phenotyping of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease using Network Modeling Approaches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COPD is an increasing global health problem of pandemic proportions, which is likely to be caused by a multitude of etiologies including environmental exposures, genetic predispositions and developmental factors. Molecular sub-phenotyping and mechanistic modeling of COPD will therefore be essential in order to develop relevant diagnostic and treatment options. The development of computational systems medicine approaches and the availability of large-scale multi-omics datasets has provided the means to elucidate systematical alterations in the complex etiology of COPD. The project combines state-of-the-art systems medicine methodology and multi-omics datasets, representing a paradigm shift in the study of COPD and obstructive airway diseases. Expected results include not only improved understanding of COPD on a systems level, but also an in-depth probing of the nature of the inflammatory process in the lung. Subsequently, the results from this study may lead to improved techniques for early diagnosis of COPD as well as novel therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COPD represents an umbrella diagnosis, with a number of different etiologies arising from an intricate interaction of environmental and hereditary factors. Two major hypotheses will be investigated: 1) we hypothesize that bridging and integration of multi-molecular- level data with environmental and clinical factors will provide improved power for subclassification and identification of COPD pathophenotypes, and that these sub-phenotypes can be investigated as function modules in molecular networks.; 2) we hypothesize that
comparative analysis of molecular networks from COPD, resilient “healthy” smokers, and never-smoker controls can lead to identification of resilience mediators potentially protecting ‘healthy’ at-risk smokers from developing disease&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary objective is to identify module-based biomarkers by integration-analysis of multi-omics data using network biology approaches, with subsequent module-based sub-phenotyping. In systems medicine, the mechanism of disease is not only caused by independent subsets of genes/proteins/metabolites identifiable by traditional statistics, but also by their interactions, making it important to develop a system-level understanding of disease. Disease subnetworks within specific cell-types, as well as exosome-mediated regulation between immune- and structural cells will be investigated. Furthermore, a probabilistic Boolean Network (PBN) model for COPD will be inferred, providing a dynamic view of pathology and potential prediction of therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@supported by ERS/EU Marie Curie postdoc followship&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Boolean network inference</title>
      <link>/project/pbn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pbn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probabilistic Boolean network inference by integrating expression with network data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probabilistic Boolean networks (PBNs) were firstly introduced by Ilya Shmulevich in 2002, to be used as a rule-based uncertainty model for gene regulatory networks or cell signaling network. It is possible to perform model training, validation and model-based prediction to investigate the dynamic behavior of cells or tissues in response to a stimulus, and to understand the mechanism of a specific phenotype. We developed a new strategy and toolbox - PBNinfer, to infer PBNs by integrating the known gene regulatory network with time-course gene expression data. Based on the inferred PBN, we could answer four kinds of biological questions: 1) prediction of direct or indirect regulators of specific targets; 2) construction of sub-models and pathways of interesting processes or functions; 3) prediction of dynamic behavior of cell based on simulation analysis in response to a stimulus, perturbed gene or a specified initial state; and 4) identification of key regulators that drive conversion between PBN states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A logical model for retinoic acid (RA) signaling based on REF data and literature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to understand the beneficial as well as the undesirable effects of treating mouse skin with tRA. We inferred a PBN for tRA-treated mouse skin with 243 genes, 518 transcriptional factor-target interactions, and 2,143 Boolean functions. It revealed multiple activation pathways for COL1A1 and COL1A2 via STAT3 consistent with well-understood literature reports. We have tested the predictions of the model with different small molecule inhibitors of STAT3 as well as inhibitors directed against other pathways that regulate COL1A1. Reliable understanding of how tRA affects the skin will lead to more rational treatments to enhance skin health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RVi33JqjOQQcSuHIBRpyTldzVkMgBVIk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Poster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
